

# Reza Mashayekhi

# Software Developer



#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

- Skilled Software Developer with 5+ years of experience in programming.
- Back-end Developer Intern @ Oracle.

Ranked 1<sup>st</sup> GPA Among the Graduated CS Students of Amirkabir University of Technology.

2020, Iran

• Awarded International Mathematics Competition (IMC) Certificate.

2010, Korea

 Only 20 middle school students, after two-stage competitive acceptance exams, were selected from Iran to participate in the IMC 2010 Korea

#### **SKILLS**

Languages Java, Python, C++, C, JavaScript, SQL, Bash, XML, HTML, CSS

**Domains** Algorithms, OOP, Agile Methodology, ML, NLP

Tools MySQL, Git, Rest API, WebGL, Linux, JSON, Jira, Jenkins, Confluence, Sonar, Bitbucket

Frameworks/Libraries Spring, Hibernate, JUnit, Mockito, React, Angular

Soft skills Problem Solving, Attention to Detail, Communication, Teamwork, Time Management

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Back-end Developer Intern**

Oracle, Canada (Remote)

- Enhanced the performance of the Data Studio web application through analysis and optimization of SQL queries (up to 5× fewer queries in one of the most commonly used endpoints).
- Developed a query counter filter and assessed queries over 130 test classes while resolving conflicting tests. This resulted in finding endpoints that need improvement and helped avoid unnecessary queries in the future.
- Resolved bugs and Implemented automated tests to ensure quality and stability.
- Java, REST API, Multi-Threading, Spring, SQL, Hibernate, Unit Testing, Git, Jira, Confluence Nov 2022 Mar 2023

#### **Back-end Developer (RA)**

University of Alberta, Alberta Machine Intelligence Institute (AMII), Canada

- Designed and developed new different ways to improve the FastMap heuristic.
- Tested new heuristics against a large number of standard benchmark problems on 395 maps in parallel.
- Attained up to 2.5× better performance. (useful in pathfinding of Video games)
- · C++, AI, Cloud Computing, Bash, Python, Automated testing

May 2021 - Oct 2022

#### **Teaching Assistant**

University of Alberta, Canada

• Introduction to the Foundations of Computation II - Python.

Jan 2021 - Apr 2022

#### **SELECTED PROJECTS**

### Simulated Different Objects Using Ray Tracing 😱

Intro to Computer Graphics course - JavaScript, WebGL, HTML

2021

Simulated Cylinder and Tetrahedron using Ray Tracing.

# Artificial Intelligence for the Reversi board-game 🕠

Al course - Java

Implemented the AI system of the Non-player-character using Minimax algorithm

#### Designing and Creating A 3NF Database From YAGO Datasets 🜎

Database course - SQL, MySQL, Python, RDBMS Design

2018

2020

 Extracted data using TSV files collected from max plank institute website. Processed and Clustered TSV files with Python and MySQL. Designed and created the databese.

#### A 2D version of the Range-Tree Data Structure 😯

Data Structures course - Java

2017

• Implemented a 2D version of the Range Tree. Queries are asked in the form of rectangle coordinates.

## **EDUCATION**

MSc in Computer Science, *University of Alberta (UofA)*, GPA 3.57/4

BSc in Computer Science, *Amirkabir University of Technology (AUT)*, GPA 18.77/20 (3.96/4)

2021 - 2022, Canada 2016 - 2020, Iran